Well, investing and trading
in the options market,
may seem somewhat
more daunting than
other asset classes
such as stocks,
bonds, exchange-traded funds,
currencies, and commodities.
You'll ultimately find that
their complexity can be
boiled down to simple
concepts you'll be able
to understand and use
the more you're exposed
to and have hands-on
experience with material.
Our aim is for you to acquire
these skills as well as the
know-how to invest in trade,
in these often complex
financial instrument.
For example, did you
know that the value of
an equity option is essentially
derived from the future
performance of a stock,
exchange traded fund,
or similar product?
This is the derivative
nature of options.
But what exactly is an option
and how do they function
as derivatives?
Why would you as an investor or
trader decide to use them?
We'll cover factors such as
these as well as many others,
and by the end of this module,
you should have the basic
language skills to enable you
to distinguish between
call and put options.
Identify the components of
an options contract of
a trading platform.
Make certain decisions about
what you're able to do in
the options market as a
contract writer or owner.
Read different stock positions,
and tell whether a given position
is in or out of the money.
I'll also present
you with some of
the benefits and
critical risks you may
face as an options investor or
trader depending on your
financial conditions,
investment objectives,
or other requirements.
We'll also give you a
broad overview of some of
the institutions involved
in the options market,
including the Options
Clearing Corporation,
and how you can access its
options disclosure document.
Which will provide
you with a host of
important insights including
margin requirements,
tax considerations,
and other topics.
As you progress
through this module,
you should start acquiring
those basic building blocks of
the options market
that will help you
advance to more
nuanced features and
complex trading strategies
specific to this asset class.
I'm Steven Levine with
Interactive Brokers,
looking forward to
your participation.